Amen. Welcome uh church family. I want
to wish you all a happy Sabbath and um
we are going to get into the word of
God. Um, immediately this morning, we
got a very special message and um I I
pray that the title of this message will
forever
be
uh written in your minds. Um, by God's
grace, this is going to be a
revolutionary
message. I want you to go ahead and hit
that like button, hit that share button,
let people know that the sermon is about
to begin. And um I'm going to be
speaking about something that uh I
believe will change the way that we
think.
And so with that said, let's pray and
we're going to get into the message
entitled
And it Was So. And it was so. Let's
pray. Heavenly Father, bless us, Lord,
as we open your word. Please, I pray,
Lord, that you would speak through me,
Lord, and that you would allow these
words, Lord, to affect every person who
hears.
May they who hear be a great multitude.
We pray it in Jesus name. Amen. Amen.
All right guys, so the message was not
entitled technical difficulties. The
message again is entitled and it was so.
And now we are about to go to our
slides. So let's go ahead pull our first
slide up. uh the title of the message
and it was so and it was so. So, we're
going to begin with Genesis chapter 1
and verse one where the Bible says, "In
the beginning,
God created the heaven and the earth.
And the earth was was without form and
void, and darkness was upon the face of
the deep. And the spirit of God moved
upon the face of the waters. And God
said, "Let there be light." and there
was light. Please, I want you to note
that God simply spoke the word and it
was so. It was so. God said, "Let there
be light." And
the words itself
had creative power so that there was
light. Let's go ahead and keep reading.
Genesis 1:7,
the Bible says, "And God made the
firmament and divided the waters that
were under the firmament from the waters
which were above the firmament. And it
was so."
It was so. Genesis 1:9, "And God said,
let the waters under the heaven be
gathered together unto one place, and
let the dry land appear." And it was so.
I want you to notice that what God said,
it was so. And when he said it, it was
so. Genesis 1 vers 11. And God said,
"Let the earth bring forth grass, the
herb yielding seed, and the fruit tree
yielding fruit after his kind, whose
seed is in itself upon the earth." And
put those words in a chat for me,
everyone. And it was so. It was so.
Genesis 1:es 14 and 15. And God said,
"Let there be firmaments in the Let
there be lights in the firmaments of the
heaven to divide the day from the night.
And let them be for signs and for
seasons and for days and for years. And
let them be for lights in the firmament
of the heaven to give light upon the
earth." And it was so. It was so.
Genesis 1 24. And God said, "Let the
earth bring forth the living creature
after his kind, and the cattle and
creeping thing, and the beast of the
earth after his kind." And it was so.
Those words, beloved, and it was so. May
these words change your life forever.
May these words alter your Christian
walk forever. Come with me to Psalm 33
and verse 6. By the word of the Lord
were the heavens made and all the host
of them by the breath of his mouth. So
we see here that the word of the Lord is
what is behind creation. The word of the
Lord, God said it and it was so. Verse 9
of chapter 33 of the book of Psalms. For
he spake and it was done. He commanded
and it stood fast. This is absolutely
crucial to understand beloved. It was
so. He spake and it was done. In Hebrews
11:3, the Bible says here, "Through
faith, we understand that the worlds
were framed by the word of God, so that
things which are seen were not made of
things which do appear." Again, Psalm
148:5, "Let them praise the name of the
Lord, for he commanded and they were
created." I want you to understand the
power of the word of God.
When God speaks it, it is so. When God
speaks it, it is so.
In fact, note with me Romans 4:1 17.
Romans 4:17 it says, "As it is written,
I have made thee a father of many
nations," speaking of Abraham, "Before
him whom he believed, even God who
quickenth the dead, and calleth those
things which be not as though they
were." God's word is so powerful
that if God promises something, then the
promise, the very word of him speaking
the promise brings the thing into
existence
at the time
at the time that he desires the thing to
come into existence. So when he said,
"Abraham, you're going to have a child."
Had God intended for Abraham uh and
Sarah to have that child at the moment
he spoke the word, they would have had a
child at the moment he spoke the word.
But God intended for that child to come
upon the scene much later. And so God
speaks the word and at the appointed
time, the thing comes to pass. Y'all put
a one in the chat if you understand the
concept that I just said. If God had
just said,
Abraham and Sarah,
you have a child.
In that instant,
it would have been, what's the word I'm
looking for, everyone?
It would have been
so.
it would have been
So, please again just note with me the
power of God's word. We're talking about
the power of God's word. The creative
power of God's word is is essential for
us to understand.
Now, now that we've set the foundation
there, I now want to introduce you to
Jesus in the flesh. This is this is that
part of the sermon. And I want you to
note with me John chapter 1 verse one.
So the Bible says here in the beginning
was the word and the word was with God
and the word was God. The same was in
the beginning with God. The same was in
the beginning with God. Now I appreciate
what the slide team is doing here
because they are reaching out to all
nationalities and I just caught that
last week. It was uh uh it was China was
the country. This week it's Jamaica. I
like that. That's that's creative slide
team. Okay.
So in the beginning was the word and the
word was with God and the word was God.
So now we understand in fact let's go
back to the screen very quickly. It says
this same was in the beginning with God.
All things were made by him and without
him was not anything made that was made.
So we now see that Jesus Jesus the son
of God
was with God.
Jesus the son of God was with God. And
now we're told that he was the word.
Meaning when he spoke when when when the
word was manifested everything was again
note with me John chapter 1 verse14
and the word was made flesh and dwelt
among us and we beheld his glory the
glory as of the only begotten of the
father full of grace and truth full of
grace and truth. So Jesus, we're being
told in John 1:14, Jesus is the word
made flesh. He is the word made flesh.
That means
that within Jesus
is the very same power that we found at
the creation.
In fact, in Desire of Ages, page 19,
Ellen White says this. By coming to
dwell with us, Jesus was to reveal both
God to men and to angels.
He was the word of God, God's thought
made audible.
Wow,
that is a powerful statement, y'all.
God's thought made audible.
In other words,
Jesus
is the thought of God made audible for
us to be able to understand God's
thoughts.
When you see Jesus, when you hear Jesus,
you are hearing the thoughts of God. Now
what I want to show you beloved is that
Jesus in himself possessed the same word
power
that we find in Genesis chapter 1. Let
me demonstrate to you. Let's go to the
book of Matthew chapter 1 and verse 40.
I'm sorry, Mark 1 and verse 40. Mark
chapter 1 and verse 40. And there came a
leper to him, beseeching him, and
kneeling down to him, and saying unto
him, If thou wilt, thou can make me
clean. And Jesus moved with compassion,
put forth his hand, and touched him, and
saith unto him,
I will
be thou clean.
And
sometime after he had spoken,
my bad. Many years after he had spoken,
my fault.
Few hours later after he had spoken, no.
And as soon as he had spoken,
immediately
it was. So y'all put that in the chat
for me, please. Immediately
it was so.
It was so. Immediately the leprosy
departed from him and he was cleansed
immediately. Let me show you another
one. Mark chapter 4 verse 38 and 39. And
he was in the hindered part of the ship
asleep on a pillow. And they awake him,
and say unto him, Master, carest thou
not that we perish? And he a arose and
rebuked the wind, and said unto the sea,
Peace be still.
And it was so.
It was so. The winds ceased and there
was a great calm. I need you to
understand that in Jesus was the very
same power creative power we find in the
book of Genesis
that it was so power that it was so word
again
Luke 7:14 and 15 I'm going somewhere
with this please follow carefully
he he came and touched the buyer and
they that bear him stood still and he
said, "Young man, I say unto thee,
arise." And he that was dead sat up and
began to speak. In other words, it was
so. And he delivered him to his mother.
Please understand
that as soon as Jesus speaks the word,
it is so.
It is so.
And now here comes
the part that begins the transformation
because I want to take you to John
chapter 2 verse one. John chapter 2
verse one.
And now get ready for this y'all. Are
y'all ready? Somebody put a put a eight
in the chat if you're ready for what
you're about to hear next. Because what
you're about to hear next
is just absolutely
This is the lynch pin, y'all. This is
everything in this sermon and your life
changing hinges upon what you're about
to hear. John chapter 2:1.
And the third day, third day there was a
marriage in Canaa of Galilee. And the
mother of Jesus was there, and both
Jesus was called and his disciples to
the marriage. And they wanted wine. The
mother of Jesus saith unto him, they
have no wine.
Jesus saith unto her,"Woman, what have I
to do with thee? My hour is not yet
come." His mother saith unto his
servants, "Whatsoever he saith unto you,
do it."
Whatsoever he saith unto you, do it.
Whatsoever he saith unto you, do it. And
there were set there six water pots of
stone. And the manner of the purifying
of the Jews containing two or three
firings a piece.
Jesus saith unto them, "Fill the water
pots with water." And they filled them
up to the brim. And he saith unto them,
"Draw out now, and bear unto the
governor of the feast, and they bear
it." And when the ruler of the feast had
tasted the water that was made wine, he
knew not whence it was. But the servants
which drew the water knew, the governor
of the feast called the bridegroom, and
saith unto him, Every man at the
beginning does set forth good wine, and
when men have well drunk, than that
which is worse, but thou has kept the
good wine until now. This beginning of
miracles did Jesus in Canaa of Galilee
and manifest manifested forth his glory
and his disciples believed on him. All
right.
What does Jesus do here? What is the
miracle?
What is the miracle here?
Y'all help me out. What is the miracle
that takes place here?
Jesus does what? He turns the water
into wine,
right?
He turns the water into wine. Now, let
me ask you something, guys. Um, how does
Jesus turn the water into wine?
How does Jesus turn the water into wine?
So, I know there's a little bit of delay
and I'm just I'm just going to wait for
you. It's okay. I'm just going to wait
for you. How does Jesus turn the water
into wine?
Okay. So, MP says he spoke
uh Patty says they obeyed
uh by his word. All right. by his word.
Now, here's my question for you. Where
in the text, where in the text does does
Jesus say, "Turn the water into wine?"
Where in the text does Jesus say, "Turn
the water into wine?"
He does not say it in the text.
All that happens in the text is Jesus
says to the servants,
"Do this.
Fill the water pots with water."
Now somewhere the water turned to wine.
And the question is how? Because Jesus
did not speak out loud.
But he spoke somewhere. Yes. Blessing.
It was a thought.
It was a thought. In other words, Jesus
thought it.
He thought it and it wasn't. He didn't
tell anyone what he was doing. Not
according to the text. He just said,
"Fill this with water."
Which means then
that Jesus does not need to audibly
speak for the thing to happen.
The word of God
just thinking a thing.
Wow.
You talk about power
to just think it and it happens.
Let's prove this. Let's go to the book
of John 11 verse 41-42. So remember this
is the resurrection of Lazarus. The
Bible says, "Then they took away the
stone from the place where the dead was
laid. And Jesus lifted up his his eyes
and said, "Father, I thank thee that
thou hast heard me."
And I knew that thou hearest me always,
but because of the people would stand
by, I said it, that they may believe
that thou has sent me.
Did y'all catch that just now?
Jesus prays to the father. He's like,
"All right, I know you already heard me.
Father, I know I know you already heard
my thought,
but I'm just going to speak out loud so
that the people can hear me when I say
the thing. So that they may know and
understand
that
that my word has power.
So if I were just to think in my mind,
Lazarus, wake up.
They may not know to attribute that to
me.
So for your sakes, I need to speak it.
Y'all put a five in the chat if you
understand what we just heard.
For your sake, I'm going to speak it so
that you can hear
which means beloved
that way back there in creation when we
read about God said let there be light.
It was not necessary for God to even
open his mouth to speak.
See beloved, don't you and I talk all
the time without using our mouths.
Don't we talk in our hearts? Don't we
think within ourselves? Don't we speak
within ourselves?
Jesus is the word of God. Had Jesus
thought in that moment, everybody wake
up. Just imagine. Had Jesus thought in
that moment, everybody wake up. What
would have happened?
Everybody
would have woken up.
Now watch this. This means that Jesus
had to control his thoughts.
Wow.
Jesus would have had to control his
thoughts and direct his thoughts. Okay,
thoughts.
Only Lazarus, wake up.
That's right. The cemetery would have
been empty.
Every grave would have been empty.
So then I need you to understand this
then that the burden that was upon Jesus
was greater than you and I can imagine
because Jesus had to be careful of every
single thought that he entertained.
Y'all put a five in the chat if you
understood what I just said.
Jesus had to be careful of every thought
that he entertained.
one careless thought.
Luke 4:1, notice with me, Luke 4:1. And
Jesus being full of the Holy Ghost,
returned from Jordan, and was led by the
Spirit into the wilderness, being 40
days tempted of the devil, and in those
days he did eat nothing. And when they
were ended, after he afterward hungered,
and the devil said unto him, "If thou be
the son of God, command this stone that
it be made bread." Now, here's what I
need y'all to understand. You you guys,
had Jesus
for a moment been like, "Yeah,
let me turn this stone to bread." Had he
thought that for a moment?
Are y'all catching what I'm saying here?
Had Jesus in his mind for a second
thought, "Yes,
I'm starving.
Let me turn this bread into wine." it. I
mean, let me turn this stone into bread.
It would have been so
it would have been so.
And now you can begin to understand the
the heavy burden that must have been on
Jesus
because his thought had power.
That's right, Keith. He couldn't even
think it or it would have happened. Now,
don't get me wrong. I'm not saying that
in his mind he could not be tempted
because he was tempted as all of us are.
But had he for a moment entertained the
temptation and said, "Yes, man. I would
really like to do this."
Can you imagine?
Can you imagine? Listen to this. Let me
show you how how.
Come with me to Luke chapter 9. Luke
chapter 9 vers 53 and 54. The Bible
says, "And they did not receive him
because his face was as though he would
go to Jerusalem." And when his disciples
James and John saw this, they they said,
"Lord, wilt thou that we command fire to
come down from heaven and consume them
even as Elias did."
Now, pause for a moment and I want you
to think just for a moment.
When when James and John say this to
Jesus, had Jesus
for a moment been like, "That's a good
idea.
I approve of this idea.
I consent
to this idea."
What would have happened in the instant
that Jesus consented to the idea
to have fire come down from heaven and
consume them?
Are y'all catching the significance?
Are you catching the significance
of what you're hearing right now?
Let me show you Colossians chapter
1:16-1 17. The Bible says, "All things
were created by him and for him, and he
is before all things, and by him all
things consist."
Meaning
in Jesus, everything that consists,
everything that is, is held together by
him. by his thoughts.
Therefore, all he needs to do,
all he needs to do
is to think you out of existence
and you would be thought out of
existence.
Did you all hear that?
If all things consist in him, in fact,
let's look at Hebrews chapter 1:3.
Hebrews chapter 1:3 who being the
brightness of his glory and the express
image of his person and upholding all
things by the word of his power. By the
word of his all things are upheld by the
word of his power.
Therefore
all it would take is a thought.
The same word that he thinks in his
mind. The same word. He doesn't have to
give an audible. All he has to do is
think it. By that same process,
all he would need to do is to think you
out of existence and you are gone. Like
a like a finger snap,
Terry.
Like a finger snap.
Remember this. Remember in John 18
verse4 as Jesus is about to be taken
captive and the Bible says uh Jesus
therefore knowing all things that should
come come upon him went forth and he
said unto them whom seek ye they
answered Jesus of Nazareth. Jesus saith
unto him I am he.
And Judas also which betrayed him stood
with them. And as soon as he had said
that unto them, I am he. They went
backward and fell to the ground. Do you
understand that Jesus could have said,
"I am he." And in the thought of, "I
want I am he to destroy you." Cuz all he
wanted there was to say, "I want I am he
to let you know that I am God."
So, I'm just going to allow a little bit
of the power of I am he. like a mini
mini many mini many mini fraction of the
word I am he just to just so you could
see that when you take me captive you're
not really taking me captive you have no
power over me at all
because had he said I am he in full
power and in full thought of I am
you in the presence of I am will destroy
you in that instant
They would have been destroyed
in that instant. They would have been
destroyed.
And so, so this sets the stage then,
beloved, for everything else you're
about to see.
Because watch this. Let's go to Matthew
chap 26:47.
And while he spake, lo Judas, one of the
twel came, and with him a great
multitude with swords and staffs
from chief priests and the elders of the
people. Now he that betrayed betrayed
him gave them a sign, saying, Whomsoever
I shall kiss, the same is he, hold him
fast. Hold him fast.
Forth with he came to Jesus and said,
Hail, Master, and kissed him. And Jesus
said unto him, "Friend, where art thou
come?" Hold on. Can we pause for a
second? Can we pause for a second?
How many of you, as I'm reading these
words, your minds are being blown right
now?
You've read these words before. We've
all read these words before. But I just
want to want to ask, how many of you, as
I'm reading these words with no
commentary, I'm just reading the words.
How many of you are like,
"What in the world?" Come on, let's keep
reading. Let's keep reading.
So Jesus said unto him, "Friend,
wherefore art thou come?" Then came they
and laid hands on Jesus, and took him.
And behold, one of them which were with
Jesus stretched stretched out his hand,
and drew his sword, and struck off a
servant of the high priest, and smold
off his ear. Then said Jesus unto him,
"Put up again thy sword into his place.
For all they that take the sword shall
perish with the sword. Thinkkest thou
that I cannot now pray to my father."
Just a thought, just a thought, and he
shall presently give me more than 12
legions of angels. But how then shall
shall the scriptures be fulfilled that
thus it must be?
In that same hour, said Jesus to the
multitude, are you come out against me
as as a thief with swords and staffs for
toate me? I sat daily with you in the
temple and ye laid no hold on me. But
all this was done that the scriptures of
the prophets might be fulfilled. Then
all the disciples forsook him and fled.
Y'all listen to me. Listen to me.
I want you to imagine the temptation
now before y'all may have y'all may have
thought had Jesus just spoken the word
you guys be destroyed like it takes
effort to like you know what let me say
it out loud. No no no no no.
Had Jesus at any moment entertained the
thought
for these enemies to be destroyed
in that instant they would have been
destroyed.
Are y'all getting this?
Are y'all catching this? Let's keep
going. Matthew 26:62 and 63. And the
high priest arose and said unto and said
unto him, Answerest thou nothing? What
is it which these witness against thee?
But Jesus held his peace.
Does that give a new meaning to you?
That Jesus held his peace.
When I was reading that this morning,
I thought to myself, I've always read
this verse, Jesus held his peace as
Jesus didn't respond to what they were
saying or Jesus was like, you know what,
I'm just going to be quiet. I've always
looked at the verse like that way. He
held his peace.
But beloved, now I'm understanding
that in this case, Jesus was controlling
himself
because
all he had to do was think, "I don't
like you guys."
All he had to do was think, "I don't
like you guys." And you understand that
when you hate someone in your heart, let
me let me pause on that for a second.
In Isaiah 53:7, he was oppressed. He was
afflicted, yet he opened not his mouth.
Do you understand that? The reason he
opened not his mouth. Now, I need Come
back. Come back for a moment. Come back
for a moment. I need you to understand
we have two mouths. How many of you know
that we have two mouths?
How many of you understand that we have
two mouths? We have this mouth
and we have this mouth
or this mouth.
right? Wherever you want to go, the the
inner mouth and the mouth of the flesh.
And so for many of us, we think
that in not speaking through the mouth
of the flesh, we're good. But God hears
the thoughts.
Had Jesus inwardly thought for a moment,
I don't like these guys and they need to
suffer for what they are doing to me. In
that moment,
the Pharisees and the Sadducees and the
leaders would have been dead.
They would have been dead. Let's keep
going. Let's keep going. The Bible says
in Luke 6:45, "A good man out of the
good treasure of his heart bringeth
forth that that which is good, and an
evil man out of the evil treasure of his
heart bringeth forth that which is evil.
For of the abundance of the heart, the
mouth speaketh." The the mouth speaks
out of the abundance of the heart
because the heart speaks first. The
heart speaks first.
Listen to this.
The Jews were continually seeking for
and expecting a divinity among them that
would be revealed in outward show. And
by one flash of overmastering will
change the current of all minds, force
from them an acknowledgment of his
superiority, elevate himself, and
gratify the ambition of his people.
This being the case,
when Christ was treated with contempt,
there was a powerful temptation before
him to reveal his heavenly character and
to compel his persecutors to admit that
he was Lord above kings and potentates,
priests and temple. But it was his
difficult task to maintain the level of
humanity.
Do y'all understand this church?
Do y'all understand the significance
the significance of what
of what we are seeing here?
had Jesus for an instant
been like, "You know what? I'm done with
y'all."
You know how we often do
with people who get on our nerves
had Jesus for a moment. Now, why did
Jesus not do that for a moment? Listen,
listen y'all. It is because he
understood the power of his thoughts
and understanding the the the the the
power of his thoughts. He didn't take
his thoughts lightly.
Listen to this. Listen to this. Desire
of Ages page 700. He knew that in a
moment by the flashing forth of his
divine power, he could lay his cruel
tormentors in the dust. This made the
trial harder to bear. Wow.
Wow.
Jesus knew
that had he merely thought,
it would have been so.
It would have been so.
Let's keep reading, y'all. Matthew 27
27-28. Then the soldiers of the governor
took Jesus into the common hall and
gathered unto him the whole band of
soldiers. And they stripped him and put
on him a scarlet robe.
And when they had platted a crown of
thorns, they put it upon his head and a
reed in his right hand. And they bowed
the knee before him and mocked him,
saying, "Hail, King of the Jews." And
they spit on him and took the reed and
smoteed him on the head. And after that
he had mocked and after that they had
mocked him they took the robe off from
him and put his put him in his own
raignment and they led him away to
crucify him.
I need you all
to put yourself in Jesus's place for a
moment with Jesus's power.
And tell me if I'm lying
when I say that these verses would never
have been in existence.
How many of you having Jesus's power
would have endured what he endured?
How many of you would have been like,
notice I didn't say anything. So, I'm
I'm I'm trying to show you what I'm
thinking.
How many of you
think about bearing that kind of
responsibility?
Matthew 27:38.
Then were the two thieves crucified with
him, the one on the right hand, the
other on the left. And they that passed
by reviled him, wagging their heads,
saying, "Thou that destroyed the temple,
build it in three days, save thyself. If
thou be the son of God, come down from
the cross." Likewise also the chief
priests, mocking him with the scribes
and elders, said, "He saved others.
Himself he cannot save. If he be the
king, himself he cannot save." Do you
understand how they are talking all of
this let's say garbage not realizing
that Jesus with a with one thought of
anger could have
could have ended their existence
and now may this verse
ring in a new way to
Here we go.
Here it is on the screen.
For God so loved the world that he gave
his only begotten son
that whosoever believeth on him should
not perish but have everlasting life.
May that verse,
May that verse ring new to you.
Because what I want you to understand,
beloved,
is that the thing that kept Jesus
from thinking evil towards us. You know,
the Bible says, "I know the thoughts
that I have towards you, thoughts of
peace and not of evil." Had Jesus
entertained thoughts of evil,
we would have been gone. What is it that
prevented him from entertaining thoughts
of evil? His love for us.
Wow.
It was love that led Jesus to guard his
every thought because he knew that one
thought could destroy us.
This is why John 14:30 Jesus could say
this. Hereafter I will not talk much
with you for the prince of this world
cometh and has nothing in me. Has how
much in me? Nothing in me. Nothing in
me. That means Jesus. Let me let me let
me let Nel White say it. The prince of
this world cometh and has nothing in me.
There was in him nothing that responded
to Satan's sophistry. He did not consent
to to sin. Not even by a thought did he
yield to temptation. Do you understand
why now? Not even by a thought did he
yield to temptation. See, I've read this
this statement before. Not even by a
thought was Jesus led to led to sin. And
I've always looked at that that phrase,
not even by a thought was Jesus led to
sin. That it was just like, "No, I'm not
sinning."
Any anybody ever had that like, "No, I'm
not I'm not sinning. You can't get me to
sin. I'm not going to sin. I'm not going
to think a bad thought and then have to,
you know, just be like, oh man, I've
sinned and fallen." I'm not going to do
that. I've always just looked at it as,
you know, a Jesus just he just wasn't he
just wasn't playing. He was about his
father's business. He wasn't playing.
But beloved, now I understand that the
reason he did not even yield to sin in
his thought is because he knew one wrong
thought,
one thought of yielding to to the to the
enemy, one thought of anger towards us,
one thought of forsaking us would have
destroyed all of humanity.
And it was his love.
It was his love that led him not to
entertain that thought. Watch this.
It was not Lord help me. How am I going
to say this?
What kept him
from not sinning in thought
is also available to us.
What motivated Jesus was love.
Wow.
What motivated Jesus
was love. Listen, even back in heaven,
God could have destroyed Desire of Ages,
page 759. God could have destroyed Satan
and his sympathizers as easily as one
can cast a pebble to the earth, but he
did not do this. When Jesus is on the
cross and his enemies are surrounding
him and they're mocking him and they're
spitting upon him and they're beating
him and all of these things, Jesus is
following the example of his father.
Jesus is showing who he was before he
came manifest in the flesh. He's showing
himself in the flesh. This is who I am.
This is love. Y'all don't understand
right now. You're doing this and that.
Y'all don't even understand that one
simple thought could destroy you. But I
love you too much to think evil against
you.
All right.
Now it's time to bring this sermon to
us.
Philippians chapter 2 verse 5.
Let this mind be in you which was also
in Christ Jesus. We could stop right
there. We could stop right there.
Let this mind be in you which was also
in Christ Jesus.
Do you understand the significance
of this verse in light of what we've
just read? In other words, God is
saying,
"I want you to have the mind that
understands that to to to think
something is for it to be so."
And though you don't have the power of
divinity to carry out immediately what
you think, you don't have that power.
You can't think a thing and it is so
immediately. No, no, no, no. You think a
thing and then you need time and effort
to bring that thing to pass.
But nonetheless, I need you to
understand that once you think the
thing, it is as good as so.
Have you ever killed anyone? No. Have
you ever killed anyone?
put a one in the chat if you ever killed
somebody.
Put a one in the chat if you have ever
killed someone. Listen to me y'all.
There will be people in the judgment who
will be condemned for murder.
Never having thought that they murdered
anybody.
Proverbs 23 verse 7.
For as he thinkketh in his heart.
The text says so is he. I'm gonna say
it is so.
It is. So,
beloved, do you understand how that
changes things for us? I think we've
heard it before. You know, um Jesus says
in Matthew 5 27, for example, you have
heard that it was said by them of old
that thou shalt not commit adultery. But
I say unto you that whosoever lookth on
a woman to lust after her has committed
adultery already with her in his heart.
We've read this verse
and maybe we've thought of it as a well
okay I mean you know doesn't really mean
that you've committed already it just
means that you know it's as good as you
listen to me
let this mind be in you which was also
in Christ Jesus
the mind Christ Jesus had was the mind
that said if I think the thing Then it
is so understand beloved that if we
start entering if we start walking in
our Christian walk with that
responsibility with that burden that if
I think the thing it is so do you
understand how many how many how much do
you understand how much less
Lord help me to phrase this right? Do
you understand how many fewer enemies we
would have?
Do you understand how many fewer people
we would hate?
Do you understand
how many fewer people we would say in
our minds, in our hearts, I hate that
guy. I hate that girl. I hate this
person. Why? Because the Bible says,
listen to this. The Bible says in 1 John
3:15, "Whosoever hateth his brother is a
murderer."
Wow.
Whosoever hateth his brother is a
murderer.
Think about you guys how many crimes
you're guilty of. Think of this. if you
had the power of Jesus. And now y'all
know for those of y'all that watched the
Sabbath school last week, you now know,
you know where this sermon is coming
from. Because when we had that
discussion about the power of the
thoughts and the snapping if we had the
power of Jesus, how many of us would
snap our fingers in our minds to get rid
of other people?
How many of us would snap our fingers
to cheat on our spouses.
How many of us would snap on our our
snap our fingers to steal and to if by a
thought you could have your neighbor's
car?
How many of you would be ever so more
careful to know as a Christian if I
think that that neighbor's without the
car and now I have his car and here I am
walking around with his car and I feel
guilty because he knows I wanted his car
and now I have it because my thoughts
have power.
Just because we cannot bring our
thoughts to pass like Jesus can doesn't
mean that we are not guilty of the sin.
Most of us
are only held back by the lack of
opportunity to do the thing that we've
already committed mentally to.
So we haven't stolen. Why? because we
really just don't want to get caught.
But if we had the opportunity to
without getting caught, if we had the
opportunity to do that thing without
getting caught, we would do that thing.
If we had the opportunity to to indulge
that thought without anybody know, we
would do that thing.
But now we're beginning to understand,
wait a minute, when I think it, it is
so.
And now that I'm walking around with
that burden of and it was so, now I'm
realizing just how careful I need to be
in my thoughts, which is why 2
Corinthians chapter 10:es 3-5 tell us
this. For though we walk in the flesh,
we do not war after the flesh. For the
weapons of our warfare are not carnal,
but mighty through God to the pulling
down of strongholds, casting down what?
Imaginations,
and every high thing that exaltth itself
against the knowledge of God, and
bringing into captivity every thought to
the obedience
of Christ.
every thought.
Now I'm understanding why my thoughts
have power.
They don't have the kind of power that
God's thoughts have. But now when I
begin to understand, let this mind be in
you, which was also in Christ Jesus, the
mind of Christ refused to think evil
because he knew that the mere thought
would bring it to pass.
He knew that had he enter had he
entertained a thought of hate.
We would have been done.
And now let me read that statement again
from the desire of ages page 123. The
prince of this world cometh said Jesus
and has nothing in me. There was nothing
in him. There was in him nothing that
responded to Satan's sophistry. He did
not consent to sin. Not even by a
thought did he yield to temptation. so
it may be with us. Christ's humanity was
united with divinity. He was fitted for
the conflict by the indwelling of the
Holy Spirit and he came to make us
partakers of the divine nature. So long
as we are united to him by faith, sin
has no more dominion over us. God
reaches for the hand of faith in us to
direct it to lay fast the hold fast hold
upon the divinity of Christ that we may
attain to perfection of character. And
now beloved again you can understand.
Wait a minute.
Just think about this.
If I had an evil thought to my child,
that thought would make my child
disappear.
Now, how many of you would have children
who disappear?
Not one.
Love would prevent you from ever
thinking an evil thought. If the love of
God is dwelling in you, it would prevent
you from thinking an evil thought to
your children,
to your spouse,
to your neighbors,
to God.
Therefore, beloved, love is the key
thing.
Did you all catch that?
If you have the power
Right now,
if the way mankind was was in the image
of God in the sense of if I think this
evil, that person disappears.
If that burden was on you
and the rule was all that needs to
happen is you need to be mad at that
person, you need to hate that person,
you need to not like that person and
that person disappears. How many of you
would from this day forward be like,
"Okay, I may not like what you're doing.
I may not like what you said."
And that's fine, but I'm not going to
hate you in my heart. Because if I hate
you in my heart, then you disappear
and then I'm guilty of killing. So
because I love God and he has told me to
love you, my love for you, even though
you're spitting on me and beating me and
taking advant
I'm not going to hate you.
Remember how sin started? How did sin
start?
Isaiah 14:13. We're almost done, you
guys. We're almost done. Isaiah 14:13.
How did sin start? For thou has said,
with your mouth.
For thou has said, with your mouth.
No, no, no, no. For thou hast said, in
thine heart, I will ascend into heaven.
I will exalt my throne above the stars
of God. I will sit also upon the mount
of the congregation in the sides of the
north. What if Lucifer had the power of
God? In the moment that he said, I will
ascend into heaven. I will exalt my
throne above the stars of God. I will
sit also upon the mount of the
congregation. In that very moment, God
would have been gone.
But Lucifer did not have the power of
God.
So time and circumstance held Lucifer's
thoughts back from coming to full
fruition. They took time. He had to
exert effort to bring his thoughts to
pass.
Not so with God.
So beloved, when we think a thing, you
got to understand that the thing that we
think, if the devil can bring about the
right circumstances, that thing is going
to come to pass. Most of the times, half
of the things we think and we we desire
after don't come to pass simply because
we don't have the opportunity.
But if you were put in the opportunity
and your mind has already made up the
decision weeks ago, months ago, years
ago,
this is why Hebrews chapter 4:12 tells
us this. For the word of God is quick
and powerful and sharper than any
two-edged sword, piercing even to the
desi dividing a sunder of soul and
spirit and of the joints and marrow and
is a discerner of the thoughts and
intents of the heart. Y'all catching
this? Come on. I just got a few more few
more verses and we're done. Let us hear
the conclusion of the whole matter. Fear
God and keep his commandments for this
is the whole duty of man. For God shall
bring every work into judgment with
every secret thing, whether it be good
or whether it be evil. Now you can begin
to understand, beloved, why a text in
the Bible like this exists. My son,
forget not my law, but let thine heart
keep my commandments.
Let thine heart keep my commandments.
There's a reason why God wants the law
written on your hearts. Jeremiah 31:33.
This is the covenant that I will make
with the house of Israel after those
days, sayith the Lord. I will put my law
in their inward parts and write them in
their hearts and will be their God and
they shall be my people. In other words,
beloved, God wants the law to be to
operate on the thought level.
Many of us keep the law on the flesh
level. All right? I'm not gonna
physically take your stuff. Okay? I'm
not gonna physically kill you. All
right? But beloved, Jesus when he came,
he said, "Listen, I need you to
understand that
that is not what counts. It counts."
Yes. But if that's all you're focused on
to the exclusion of the law being
written
actually in the heart,
meaning I realize
that my thoughts must be guided by the
law. And now it's no longer a matter of
I can't do this because I don't want to
sin. No, it's a matter of whoa, if I
hate this brother, then he's dead.
I've killed him. Yeah, he still walk
around in the flesh, but it is as though
I have killed him. And I'm not a
murderer. I'm a Christian.
No, I'm not murdering him. You want me
to do what? Sin. You want me to do what?
You want me to murder him? Nah, not
happening. Not happening. I'm a follower
of Jesus. You want me to steal that
guy's car? You want me to steal his
house?
Nope. Why would I do that?
Why would I do that?
You You You actually want me to go kill
him? No. No. Just think it. Just think
it and he's dead. No.
No. I'm I can be upset at what he's
doing, but nah,
no. I'm not going to think evil.
I will not entertain you, Satan, even in
thought.
And now the burden of having to be like,
okay, how can I overcome sin? How can I
do? How can I? No. Now that burden is
gone. And now all you realize is, hey,
if I have love in my heart, I am not
going to think evil against my neighbor.
I'm not going to tr try to take my
neighbor's stuff.
I'm not going to have anger towards Noah
because that's not who I am. I'm a
Christian. I'm not perfect,
but I'm a Christian. I'm a follower of
Jesus. And I'm just not if go if if if
if God is going to call me perfect, let
let him call me perfect. All I know is
that I'm not going to kill you and I'm
not going to bear false witness against
you and I'm not going to hate you. I'm
not going to coveret against you. No,
I'm just not going to do those things.
I'm not saved on my own righteousness
cuz I my righteous are as filthy rats.
But I can tell you this. I will not
entertain you even in thought, Satan. I
just won't do it.
1 Peter chapter chapter 2 verse one. We
got two more verses after this. We are
done. For even here unto were you
called. Because Christ also suffered for
us, leaving us an example that you
should follow in his steps. Who did no
sin, neither was Gile found in his
mouth. See those two different things.
Who did no sin, neither was Gile found
in his mouth, neither of his mouth, not
the fleshly mouth, and not the mouth of
his mind. Watch this. who when he was
reviled reviled not again.
When he suffered he threatened not
because had he threatened they would
have been gone. But he committed himself
to him that judges righteously who in
his own self bear our sins in his own
body on the tree that we being dead to
sin should live unto righteousness by
whose stripes we are healed. You guys,
this is I hope you see this is
revolutionary, mindblowing, mindchanging
stuff.
Now we can understand why the seal of
God in Revelation 7 is placed
in the mind.
Now I understand why Revelation 7:1, the
four winds are being held back.
I saw another angel ascending from the
east having the seal of the living God.
And he cried with a loud voice to the
four angels to whom it was given that
heard the earth and the sea saying hurt
not the earth neither the sea nor the
trees till we have sealed the servants
of our God in their foreheads. You're
sealed in the forehead. Meaning I will
not entertain
any thought of harm to my neighbor.
That's it.
Wow. I will not take advantage. I will
not entertain any thought. I will not
covet. I because every one of those
every every thought is hurting somebody
else.
I won't do it.
I may have my issues. I may have my
struggles. I know. But here's one thing
I'm not going to do. Satan, I'm not
going to entertain your thoughts. And
you will find that in not entertaining
the thoughts of Satan.
I mean, let God say it. You don't say
it, but let God say, "Have you consider
considered my servant? Have you
considered my children? How they're
faithful to me?" You can't even get them
to follow you in thought.
Yes, everybody will be tempted. You'll
be tempted to think. You'll be tempted
to do all kinds of things. That's we're
human. We're all going to face
temptation.
But you could say in your mind, you know
what? As appealing as as that may may be
or look to the flesh, I'm saying no.
I'm not going to entertain it right
here. I'm not going to consent to it
right here. I've already made up my
mind. Not happening.
By the grace and power of God, through
the love of Jesus, it's not happening.
Put a one in the chat if you are ready
to let this mind be in you which was in
Christ Jesus. If you are ready to say,
"Lord, help me to live as though my
thoughts
have the power of life and death in
them. Help me to live, Jesus, with the
same burden that you lived with
so that I will not
I will not entertain the devil's
suggestions in my mind." And if I can
beat the devil here, I've already beaten
him in the flesh.
I see the ones coming in the chat. I see
the ones coming in the chat. Um,
I hope this message changes the way you
think.
think. Put it in the chat, everyone. And
it was so.
Walk with those words.
No, if I hate that brother, may as well
say, and it was so.
Help the it was so to be for
righteousness sake, not for wickedness
sake. Help me to wish good on people.
Help me to think well of people. Help me
to love people despite sometimes their
unlovable natures. Help me, Lord, to
have the mind of Jesus. Heavenly Father,
thank you for speaking to us.
Bless us with your mind. May we carry
the burden of understanding the power of
our thoughts.
And in carrying this burden, may it
change the way we think.
May we not snap our fingers
and exercise the power of destruction
and theft and lying and adultery and
stealing and killing,
coveting.
But Lord, may we resist the enemy
because of our love for you and our love
for our neighbor.
In Jesus name we pray.
put the mind of Jesus in us and let us
live by it.
In Jesus name we pray. Amen.
Um beloved, uh we're going to go ahead
and put the uh
put the uh link for uh the the Zoom I'm
sorry, the Mighty Networks. I'm sorry.
We're going to put the link for the
Mighty Networks uh into the chat so that
you could join us on afterlow and we can
discuss the Sabbath school as well as
the sermon. And uh I pray that again
this message uh has touched your life uh
in a way that will change the way that
you see things and the way that you walk
in your Christian walk today. So may God
bless you and uh we will see you again
next Sabbath. Please let people know
about Living Mana Church. invite people,
tell them to get on Mighty Networks and
just see what we have going on here um
in our online church. May you be blessed
and I'll see you next week.
Thank you for joining us today. If this
is your first time worshiping with us,
please check out our website at
livingmana.urch.
We are not just here for Sabbath
service. We have weekly programming too
that covers mental health, physical
health, weekly prayer service, financial
health, and proving the existence of
God. It is our desire that our
programming will continue to bless you.
Please continue to pray for us as we
fulfill God's mission to go into all the
world with the gospel of Jesus Christ.
[Music]